<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nolan Feeny - Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2018-08-05T12:34:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Week 4</title><link href="/week-4.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-05T12:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-05T12:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>nolanfeeny</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-08-05:/week-4.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Berlin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we’ve done in Berlin this week is have a lot of class. Basically the goal by the end of the “semester” is to take given data from Traverse City regarding sun and wind speeds, and to model how to best implement a renewable energy system …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Berlin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we’ve done in Berlin this week is have a lot of class. Basically the goal by the end of the “semester” is to take given data from Traverse City regarding sun and wind speeds, and to model how to best implement a renewable energy system. This includes how many wind turbines / solar panels to build, and the averages including initial cost and expected benefit, both in terms of sustainability and the financial economy. At the end, we’ll have simulated multiple models and recommend a few optimal scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="wind" src="/images/wind.jpg" width="700"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did take a day field trip into a small town called Feldheim. They have around 140 people in population, and operate completely on renewables (wind, solar, biogas). They also produce 250x the amount of electricity that they need every year. Something to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Mannheim / Ludwigshafen&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to Ludwigshafen in 2014, as part of an Okemos high school exchange program with my orchestra. During that time, I had a host family take me in very welcomingly and give me a very short preview of their culture. We’ve stayed in occasional contact, and the same student came to Okemos to stay with me for a week the following year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="mannheim" src="/images/mannheim.JPG" width="700"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend I went back to stay with that family and they took me in just as graciously as they did before. It’s pretty amazing, because had that program not existed these are people that I would never have a relationship with, but because I do I’ve had opportunities that I would normally never have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was more of a relaxing weekend - a more settled down lifestyle than living in the bigger/busier city of Berlin. Traveling usually provides no rest for me, and that wasn’t the case this time. It was so cool to see everything look the same as 5 years ago. Honestly, I probably changed more than the city did. I also spoke German almost the whole weekend without using English, which to me was an accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Week 3</title><link href="/week-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-30T12:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-30T12:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>nolanfeeny</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-30:/week-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Limited traveling this week. Stayed in Berlin for the weekend, which gave me a chance to learn more about culture and way of life in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="olympic pool" src="/images/IMG_2852.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olympic Stadium pool: So cool. I didn’t know the architecture was designed by Nazis, but it was indeed intimidating. Shout out Jesse …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Limited traveling this week. Stayed in Berlin for the weekend, which gave me a chance to learn more about culture and way of life in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="olympic pool" src="/images/IMG_2852.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olympic Stadium pool: So cool. I didn’t know the architecture was designed by Nazis, but it was indeed intimidating. Shout out Jesse Owens. My left ear hearing was muffled for the next week though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church: next to a giant cathedral that was making bell sounds at the start of the service, which was almost like being in a Game of Thrones episode. Inside the newer functional church, there weren’t many people. Probably mostly tourists, but who knows. I understood enough German to realize that the pastor was speaking on how world leaders should be helping others in need, especially in underdeveloped countries such as Africa. This is interesting, tying politics and religion together since they’re so separate in America. However, Germany is currently a Christian democratic union, and I personally believe that the values, implemented without corruption, would have a beneficial impact on society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="cathedral" src="/images/IMG_2845.jpg" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also learning about general culture and how it shapes the mindset of the people that live here. Everyone I’ve seen takes more responsibility for themselves and how they affect others. For example, the amount of people riding bikes, the rules regarding bike lanes, and sorting trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Class is conceptually so interesting and applicable to what I want to do with my life. We’re taking multiple scenarios regarding renewable energy, and simulating how they work in the real world. These simulations include how much energy is harvested based on the model of wind turbines or solar cells, how much is input into the grid, and the economics of the systems. It has been mostly Matlab, but also using some excel. The lectures, however, suck. This is because the German lecturers don’t speak the greatest english, so they are taking a lot of time reading slides that I’d personally be better off reading on my own. They also don’t always understand the questions that I ask, and start to explain something that I already understand. Still though - overall, it’s a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also learning about myself. I have become a decent cook in recent weeks, because otherwise I would be broke or starving. Mainly have been making pasta with sauce and chicken strips or fish sticks, with frozen mixed vegetables and milk or fruit juice. Trying to be healthy. Since I don’t have a gym membership, I’ve been doing either 100 pushups or 50 pull-ups every single day when I wake up, which tbh is a good way to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Week 2</title><link href="/week-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-23T12:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-23T12:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>nolanfeeny</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-23:/week-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much happened in Berlin this week, but this weekend I went to a pretty cool city. I’ll talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;AMSTERDAM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="painting" src="/images/am_painting.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam was probably the coolest city I’ve been to in my life. The train ride into the main city was nothing special. Then I walked out …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not much happened in Berlin this week, but this weekend I went to a pretty cool city. I’ll talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;AMSTERDAM&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="painting" src="/images/am_painting.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amsterdam was probably the coolest city I’ve been to in my life. The train ride into the main city was nothing special. Then I walked out of the station and the city just blind sided me. I’ve never seen such a vibrant and alive place before. For the weekend, we stayed at a hotel and spent the days in the city, and the last day at the beach. Some things I noticed - art is a central pillar to the culture of the city. Everywhere you go, buildings are designed to be aesthetically pleasing, there are live musicians, and many free open art galleries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="garden" src="/images/am_garden.jpg" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture took place between the Van Gogh and the Rijks Museums. We went to the Van Gogh, and I wasn’t expecting much. Just a lot of portraits and starry night. Maybe it was just my low expectations, but I’ve never seen art so good before. There was something about it that really resonated with me. Not the portraits as much, but all of the peasant/rural scenery was almost dreamlike. Very glad I got to see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="canal" src="/images/am_canal.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went on a boat ride through the canals, and that was very relaxing. It was a good way to see a completely different perspective of the city architecture. The transition from modern buildings to old Anne Frank resemblant ones was really cool. Amsterdam has so many different facets and options on which to build your lifestyle. The next night I went to a casino for free and won 10 euros. Not a big baller lol. Definitely want to go back some day, especially during the winter.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Week 1</title><link href="/week-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-07-16T12:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T12:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>nolanfeeny</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-07-16:/week-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Iceland&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Harbor" src="/images/harbor.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way to Berlin, I had a 19 hour layover in Iceland from July 5-6. Coincidentally, my uncle and two of his friends were also in Iceland during my time, so they were able to show me around Reykjavik. I arrived at around 11 am - most of my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Iceland&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Harbor" src="/images/harbor.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way to Berlin, I had a 19 hour layover in Iceland from July 5-6. Coincidentally, my uncle and two of his friends were also in Iceland during my time, so they were able to show me around Reykjavik. I arrived at around 11 am - most of my time was spent in the city near the harbor, and I was able to go on a whale watching boat ride, and saw a minke whale and puffins which were pretty cool. The harbor had a lot of restaurants with different themes: I ate at a Haitian cafe and had dinner at a place called ‘Salt’, which had the best bread and butter I’ve ever had in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Restaurant" src="/images/salt.jpg" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed the night at a ‘hotel’, which was really more like a bed &amp;amp; breakfast without the breakfast. It was super nice though, and the ability to take a shower and sit in a hot tub while the sun was shining at midnight was really cool. At about 4 am I went back to the airport to head off to Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hotel" src="/images/hotel.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One extra note about Iceland - it has a lot of renewable energy sources, especially with long daylight hours, available water, windy bluffs, and geothermal springs. I believe has the potential to run completely on renewable energy, and to be a world leader in the progression of that movement. At some point I really want to go back and work on implementing that on a national scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, next city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Berlin&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graffiti" src="/images/market.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin is &lt;em&gt;dope&lt;/em&gt;. There’s such a huge variety of culture, both seen in people and the environment. It’s awesome how I can be in a food market, a historical monument, in the middle of the city, or in a secluded park, and no matter where I am there’s so much spirit and enjoyment of my surroundings. I’ve noticed that people use bikes and public transit way more than I’ve seen back home, and there are pet dogs everywhere. There’s also a lot of graffiti, some of which is really aesthetic and some of which is just objectively not haha, but it really does fit the rebellious nature of the city and its history. I have way too many pics, probably just gonna make an album on facebook when I get back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Graffiti" src="/images/graffiti.jpg" width="350"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first week, I’ve been taking language classes. I took German in high school, so I’m a bit familiar with the language and the class that I’m in doesn’t use any english, which is pretty cool. I can get around the city with my German, but it helps that all the younger locals also know english. We’ve been taking classes in the morning from 8:30 - noon, and I live in an apartment off campus so I need to get up around 7 and use public transportation (UBahns, free for students) to get to class. Then in afternoons we’ve been going on tours of Berlin. Monday was a river tour on a boat, with a buffet and some good wine &amp;amp; desert. Vegetables taste amazing here. We have also been on a walking tour, and seen many of the historic landmarks in Berlin including the Berlin Wall, the Holocaust memorial, the square of the book burnings, and many others. These memorials have been extremely moving to me personally, which was unexpected for me. It’s serious history, and there’s something very haunting and reverential about it. We’ve visited the Reichstag, the building for the German parliament, and went up to the top, where there is a huge glass dome and a view of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Hotel" src="/images/memorial.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The renewable energy simulation lab starts next week, and will use a lot of Matlab/Simulink combined with knowledge and math regarding renewable sources and energy grids. I’ll also get into the swing of daily life, which will be an interesting transition. I’m very excited for what’s to come, don’t want it to go too fast, but also can’t wait to come home and be back in America.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Pre Study Abroad</title><link href="/pre-study-abroad.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-29T12:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-29T12:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>nolanfeeny</name></author><id>tag:None,2018-05-29:/pre-study-abroad.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The reason I made this blog is because I'm going to be leaving the U.S. to study abroad in Berlin, Germany from July 7 - August 18. Since I won't have regular access to my phone, I'm not sure how accessible I'll be. Facebook isn't usually where I want to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The reason I made this blog is because I'm going to be leaving the U.S. to study abroad in Berlin, Germany from July 7 - August 18. Since I won't have regular access to my phone, I'm not sure how accessible I'll be. Facebook isn't usually where I want to post updates because I don't like flooding other people with stuff about myself, so I plan on keeping a regular update of how I'm doing here on my website. That way if anyone is genuinely interested in what I'm up to, they'll be able to know what's going on in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try to post updates and pictures here, which will be good for me keeping my "coding" skills fresh. I'm looking to improve my German, which is one of the classes I'm taking. The other one is a renewable energy simulation lab, so if that's interesting I'll talk more about it in the future. I might post the links to this website as well on facebook whenever I do update, so be on the lookout for that if you're interested. Thanks for reading these couple paragraphs, if you did it means a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>